

CONTACT

- Porto, Portugal
- **□** +351 91 615 15 65
- ✓ ricarraf@gmail.com
- /ricardojaferreira
- / / Ricardo Araujo Ferreira

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES



TECHNOLOGIES

Django • React • Spring •
Jest • Apache Storm •
Apache Cassandra • Apache •
Nginx • Git • MySql /
MariaDB • PostgreSQL •
MongoDB • Docker • Kafka •
Couchbase • Hazelcast •
Jenkins/CircleCI • Cucumber

LANGUAGES



OPERATING SYSTEMS







ACTIVITIES



See the extended version at https://git.io/fh5zG.

Ricardo Jorge de Araújo Ferreira

Informatics and Computing Engineering (M.Sc.) Electrical and Computer Science Engineer (M.Sc.)

SUMMARY

I am currently working as an Engineer Manager in an Agile environment with modern technologies, privileging good quality code and architectures, and helping to build a state-of-the-art AI tool. I have worked with many technologies and I am always open to adding new ones to my portfolio.

EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager

2023/06 - now

Hyperscience, Ltd

New York, USA (Remote)

- Hands on leader of a team with 6 developers and 2 QA engineers
- Leading and implementing the application support program

Software Engineer

2021/06 - 2023/06

Hyperscience, Ltd

New York, USA (Remote)

- Designing abstractions, APIs and tools to connect with ML modules
- Development of the intelligent document processing (IDP) tool written in Python using Django

Backend Engineer

2019/12 - 2021/06

Paddy Power Betfair & FanDuel - Flutter Entertainment Plc Porto, Portugal

- Execute full software development life cycle in a microservices architecture that processes 135M transactions every 24h
- Worked on teams with the DevOps culture

Web Engineer - Fullstack Developer

2018/02 - 2019/12

Jumia - Porto Tech Center

Porto, Portugal

R&D - Engineer

2012/01 - 2018/02

Institute for Systems and Computer Engineering

Porto, Portugal

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Informatics and Computation Engineering

2020

Faculdade de Eng. da Universidade do Porto

Porto, Portugal

- Main topics: Software Architectures, Computation Theory, Algorithms, Discrete Mathematics, Formal Tests in Software, Operating Systems;
- Thesis: Recovery of Software Architectures (17 out of 20)

M.Sc. in Electrical and Computers Engineering

2008

Faculdade de Eng. da Universidade do Porto

Porto, Portugal

Thesis: Solar Car - Control and development. (17 out of 20)